My name is Johan Casselgren and I am a snow physicist.
On the snow lab we try to map and determine different types of snow.
Much like Linnaeus did with animals and plants.
In the traces of climate change-
-is the need to understand the characteristics of the snow.
-Then the need for artificial snow is increasing.
One is looking for answers on how snow acts as material-
-and how to create safer winter tires, skis with more gliding-
-or understand how avalanches work.
Knowledge that can both save lives and provide more Olympic medals.
We want to understand how the snow is created in the atmosphere-
-From molecules to snowflakes and snow cover.
The snow crystals are formed in the clouds when water vapor becomes drops that freeze.
Snow crystals have a hexagonal basic structure that gives beautiful designs.
The shape is due to the water molecules binding so to each other-
-When the positive hydrogen atoms attract the negative oxygen atoms.
Successfully, a hexagonal slice are built up where the molecules get easier.
Depending on whether the hexagon grows on width or height-
-Can the snow crystals just as well be tube -shaped or disc shaped.
The shapes depend on how water drops attach to the snow star and grow.
About one hundred thousand water drops are required to form a snowflake.
Down on the ground, the snow crystals are starting to form more and more round grains.
We go from looking at snow crystals to seeing the snow as a material.
This is what we are researching: how the crystals affect each other.
The love of snow and man's relationship with the white is old.
For example, the oldest ski in the world has actually been found in Sweden.
A thousand years older than the pyramids.
But it was not until the 20th century that the snow came to be about entertainment-
-With the growth of winter tourism.
The second hunt within skiing-
-Have made the snow increasingly interesting to research.
Now you try to find the recipe for artificial snow with good slide.
A fair snow that does not change during competition.
We look at different preparation methods for skis.
The skis can be one to two seconds faster per kilometer-
-So that we can get even more medals in the ski gate next Olympics.
In dead snow, the snow grains do not attach to each other.
Moisture has been pushed out and makes the track porous.
The downhill is looking for the dry snow in the hunt for the best powder.
-We measure with the fluff act.
-Fluffactor?
It describes how much snow it gets on the ground when the snow crystals land.